# 软炸鱼条
Soft-Fried Fish Fingers
# 又是好吃的 好吃的吧
- Tasty stuff again? - Tasty, isn't it?
# 这个软炸鱼条主要是告诉大家
I cook this soft-fried fish fingers
# 怎么调这糊
In order to show you how to make the batter
# 是软炸的都得用这个方法来做
You need to use it for all soft-fried stuff
# 今天大爷用鱼做这道菜
Today Da Ye will use fi
# 这鱼肉可以用黄鱼 桂鱼
Fish can be yellow croakers or Chinese perches
# 尽量找刺少的
Try to find those with fewer bones
# 下面咱就开始
Now let's begin
# 今天大爷选这鱼是海鱼
Today I pick a sea fish
# 把头去了
Its head has been removed
# 这个鱼肉看 雪白
See, the fish looks brightly white
# 从脊背给它剖开
Slice it open along its back
# 肉挺厚的
The meat is quite thick
# 这黑膜不要紧一会咱给它片下去
Don't worry about this black film. I'm gonna cut it off later on
# 看着不好吃 没法吃（*我看了半天也没懂为什么要插这么一句
It looks not good. Not really edible
# 剔这个鱼骨头就贴着鱼的中骨
When you remove the fish bone, hold your knife close to the mid-bone
# 这网友们都会
Your fans all know how to do so
# 黑膜去掉
Remove the black film
# 有的鱼肚皮上有点小刺
Some fish has little splinters on its belly
# 我们把它剔掉
Let's cut them off
# 这个鱼皮也不要
Discard the fish skin also
# 有的鱼也可以要 比如黄鱼
You may keep it when you choose other kind of fish like yellow croakers
# 因为黄鱼肉太嫩
The meat of yellow croakers is too soft
# 有那个皮它不容易碎
The skin can keep it from disintegrating
# 切好了 我把这鱼洗洗
- You're done with cutting? - I'm gonna wash the fish
# 大爷在家做饭
Da Ye cooking at home
# 跟在外边做饭不一样
is not the same as cooking else where
# 喜欢在家做饭吗 喜欢啊
- Do you like cooking at home? - Of course
# 在家做饭是一种享受
Cooking at home is a kind of enjoyment
# 软炸鱼条 就得条啊
Soft-fried fish fingers, you need to cut the fish into small sticks
# 长短得一致
Of the same length
# 得让它整齐
You need to have it neat
# 切成条状
Cut into small sticks
# 软炸鱼 鸡胸肉或鸡腿肉
Soft-fried fish, or chicken breast or leg
# 都是这样 也切条
Are (prepared) in the same way, cut into small sticks
# 切好了
It's done
# 大爷干活就是麻利
Da Ye is such a quick and neat chef
# 来点姜 姜片 来点葱 葱段
Get some ginger, ginger slices. Cut some scallions
# 介绍一下调料要哪些
Would you introduce the seasoning ingredients to us?
# 先放盐
First the salt
# 上次烙肉饼的时候
Last time when I was frying meat pie
# 有的网友说大爷搁盐太多了
Some fans said that I've used too much salt
# 现在的盐不咸 多搁一点
The salt we use nowadays is not very flavourful, so I use a bit more
# 白胡椒 黄酒 都是少许
White pepper powder, yellow cooking wine, a little
# 给它抓拌一下
Grab and mix thoroughly
# 腌十分钟十五分钟就可以
And wait for 10 or 15 minutes
# 咱们利用这个环节
At this step
# 大妈要给大爷擦汗
Da Ma's gonna wipe away Da Ye's sweat
# 对擦擦汗
Yeah, wipe the sweat away
# 利用这个环节擦擦汗
Use this time to wipe the sweat
# 这不行 这汗太多了
This is not working. You're sweating too much
# 利用腌制的环节
Take the time of marinating
# 我们开始调糊 软炸糊啊
We start to make the batter, soft frying batter
# 我们这糊里边有
We have many kinds of batter
# 软炸糊 酥炸湖 高丽糊 淀粉糊
Soft frying batter, Crisp frying batter, "Gao Li" batter, starch batter
# 根据不同菜肴的口感和名称
Dependent on the taste and name of different dishes
# 用不同的糊
We use different kinds of batter
# 还有蛋清糊
There is one other kind, egg white batter
# 72
# 00:03:07.440,00:03:08.560
# 蛋清糊就用纯蛋清
which uses egg white only
# 面粉 搁多少面粉啊
Flour, how much flour do we need?
# 这里边搁三分之二的面粉
Two third of this is flour
# 很快 搅匀
Stir and mix it, be fast
# 越说麻利就是越麻利
You work is even quicker and neater than I've said
# 好厨师都是夸出来的
Compliments make a good chef
# 三分之二的面粉
Flour takes up 2/3
# 三分之一的淀粉
One third is starch
# 这就是玉米淀粉
This is corn starch
# 淀粉是起脆的
The starch makes the crust more crispy
# 因为面粉它劲大（啥是劲大？我意译成了面筋（。
Because of the gluten in flour
# 有时候你和的太干了以后
Sometimes if you use too much flour
# 它成了囫囵面糊了（面团？面糊？ 少搁点水
The batter would be too dense and thick. Add in a little bit water
# 小苏达 这小苏打不能太多
Baking soda. Don't use too much
# 看着 大约在两克三克就行了
See, 2g or 3g is just fine
# 苏打发起什么作用
What's the effect of baking soda?
# 起饱满胀发还有发脆的作用
It helps the batter swell up and make the crust crispy
# 这时候我们给它调一调
Now we mix it up
# 还要搁一点油
We still need a bit oil
# 花生油
peanut oil
# 这糊就好了
And the batter is done
# 我们让它饧一会我们就开始炸了
Let it rest a while and we'll start frying
# 这搁油是为什么呢
What's the effect of
# 也起一个膨胀 脆的作用
It also helps swelling and makes the crust crispy
# 咱们转移
We move to the stove
# 大妈给点上火 瞧瞧
Da Ma helps me lit the fire, see
# 腌好了 把那葱姜都弄出去是吧
The marinating is finished. Remove the ginger and scallions, right?
# 这个菜在家里特别实用
This dish is particularly suitable for home-cooking
# 也比较好操作
And it is quite easy to cook
# 老人孩子都爱吃
Children and the old would love it
# 烧热倒油 倒多少油
- Heat up the wok and pour the oil in. - How much oil do we need?
# 炸东西油得宽敞点
We need broader oil for frying
# 油温呢 这个油温稍微的等一等
What about the oil temperature? We wait for a while
# 得到四五成热
It needs to be heated to 120-150°C
# 看着啊 蘸糊
Take a look, dip into the batter
# 蘸糊是以什么为准呢
How do you make sure that the meat is wrapped well with the batter?
# 这挺关键的
This is crucial
# 它不能马上跟一条线似的
That the batter should not drip immediately
# 就流下来了
like a thread
# 又能覆在上边
And as long as it can wrap the meat
# 但是它又往下流
as well as dripping down
# 稀稠的这个度就可以
the thickness of the batter is just well
# 另外有时候我们的鱼 比如龙利鱼
And sometimes the fish we use, for instance, flatfish
# 有的鱼水分可能大一点
Its meat contains more water
# 这糊就得稠一点
Then the batter has to be thicker
# 要不它挂不住
or else it cannot stick to the meat
# 挂糊
wrap the meat with batter
# 这油温行么 油温四成 可以
Is this temperature alright? - 120°C, right
# 这个东西就是
This thing is
# 有的在家里吃 吃的实在点
Sometimes when you cook at home, you would prefer a more genuine taste
# 别挂好多糊
Don't wrap it with too much batter
# 吃的不是鱼了 全是面糊了
Otherwise you're not having fish, but the batter and crust
# 吃不着鱼味了
without the taste of fish
# 有网友说把这鱼搁
Some fans may ask if we can put the fish
# 糊里边一块行不行 行
altogether into the batter, if this can do. This is ok
# 但是它有时候不好看
But it does not always look good
# 还是一根一根的一条一条的好
It's better to do it one by one
# 但是牛肉或者猪肉
But for beef or pork
# 不能搁里头 搁里头血水一出去
It should not be drown in the batter, otherwise the bloody fluid would come out
# 影响它的颜色
Which changes the colour of the batter
# 搅一搅 拌一拌 上颜色了
Mix and stir, the colour
# 先定型 这是定型 要两次炸熟
- First we set the shape. - This is for setting the shape. - It needs to be fried a second time
# 两次炸熟时候
When you fry it the second time
# 外边可能还有个小尾巴小揪揪
It may leave a little "tail" outside
# 还给它掰一掰
You can break it off
# 真好看
It looks so nice!
# 大爷这手老抖
Da Ye's hands are shaking all the time
# 网友都心疼你了知道吗
Do you know your fans really care about you
# 没毛病 大爷没毛病 好着呢
No problem, Da Ye's alright. Can't even feel better
# 对你要说一下
Indeed, you should clarify that
# 马上就好了
Will be finished soon!
# 鱼不能腌咸了
The fish should not be marinated with too much salt
# 不够咸怎么办 蘸椒盐
What if it's not salty enough? Eat with some pepper-salt
# 复锅了 真好诶
Back to the wok, nice!
# 好了关火
Ok, turn off the fire
# 炸至金黄色
Fry it until golden
# 这一斤鱼肉炸一大盘子
One Jin (=500g) fish fills this large plate
# 摆摆盘 好了
Let's set the plate.
# 是不是特成就感
Such an achievement, isn't it?
# 照一个 好了 瞧瞧
Take a shot, ok, see
# 我们可以享用了
We can now enjoy this dish
# 又该高呼我们的口号了 什么
Slogan time again. What is it?
# 家有大厨 就是幸福
Master chef in family, blessed is your life!
# 跟网友说一下 拜拜
Tell your fans, bye!
# 拜拜
Bye bye!
# 大妈幸福吧
Da Ma's so blessed, isn't she?
# 拜
Bye
# 问答时间：为什么烙饼时葱要后放
Q&A time: the right time to mix in scallions in cooking meat pie
# 葱花肉饼 要放更多的大葱
Meat pie with scallions, we need scallions as much as possible
# 大葱呢 不要过早地把它拌在肉馅里头
As for the scallions, you should not mix them into the meat mince too early
# 一个是 肉馅呢 我们事先调好味儿
On the one hand, the meat mince, we season it in advance
# 根据肉馅 有的肉呢可能
According to the kind of meat you choose, some kinds are probably
# 含水量高 我们就不打水了
more watery, and we need water no more
# 如果含水量高我们就不打水了
We do not use more water if the meat has much in it already
# 如果有的肉呢比较好
Some kinds are of a better quality
# 含水量比较低
containing less water
# 肉呢显得有点老 发柴
the meat taste a little bit chewy
# 肥的少 瘦的多
and has a much larger proportion of lean meat than fat
# 我们适量还要打一点水
We still need a proper amount of water
# 主要打馅儿 主要是（？） 酱油
Seasoning the meat mince, we mainly use light soy sauce (?)
# 老抽
and Dark soy sauce
# 盐
salt
# 少搁一点点味精
a little bit MSG
# 味精呢因为少量地用是没问题的
As for MSG, because it's alright to use just a little bit
# 然后胡椒
And then pepper
# 顺时针 啊 把这肉馅打个劲
Clockwise, toss the meat mince until elastic
# 摔
Toss it
# 摔到有劲了
until it is elastic
# 这个肉呢我们就要用油给它封上
And this meat we should seal it with a layer of oil
# 然后把 姜 葱
And then ginger, scallions
# 因为要用大量的葱
Because we need lots of scallions
# 这个葱呢 就搁在这个肉（？）头
which is to be put (?)
# 是吧
Right?
# 这个因为葱过早的放入肉馅里边儿
Because the scallions are mixed into the mince too early
# 经过这个腌制以后呢
After marinating
# 这个葱呢有点儿臭葱味
The scallions would give a bad smell
# 所以要搁在（？）
So they has to be put (?)
# 什么时候把面都和好了 都醒好了
When you have finished making the dough, and it has rested for a while
# 也擀出这个劲儿来了
and has been rolled until al dente
# 然后这时候我们再把葱和到肉里边儿
Now we can mix the scallions into the mince
# 再下来的话呢
What's next?
# 我们应该说是
we should say
# 呃 根据不同的环境我们应该是
According to different circumstances we should be like
# 烙多少饼 和多少葱
The amount of scallions should correspond to how many pies you're gonna make
# 这样能保证葱 它的香味儿
This can ensure the aroma of the scallions
# 有的烙得比较合适的时候
If you get the frying well
# 那个葱出来是刚刚好
The scallions would end up being just right
# 葱香味足
Full of the aroma, and the taste is strong
# 如果说过早和到这个肉馅儿里的话
If you mix them too early
# 葱呢有点儿臭葱味了
The scallions would smell bad
# 需要我们的网友呢在实际操作当中
So our friends, in your cooking, you need to
# 要灵活地掌握这些环节
grasp these steps and practice them in a flexible way
# 比如说韭菜
for instance, garlic chives
# 你过早地和行不行啊
Can you mix them into the mince a bit early?
# 所以这韭菜呢
So the chives
# 是韭菜馅呢
used to make the mince stuffing
# 饺子也好包子也好或者是馅饼也好
No matter you're making dumplings, buns, or pies
# 不要过早地把它和进来
It won't do if you mix them in too early
# 应该把面都准备好了
Only when the dough is ready
# 锅也烧好了
and the wok has been heated up
# 再把韭菜和到这个肉里头
can you mix the chives into the meat mince
# 这韭菜出来以后香味刚刚好
So that you can get the right taste of the chives
# 希望大家呢在用的时候呢
I hope that when you guys are cooking
# 一定要灵活
remember to be practice these tips flexibly